jaiku.com 2007-12-24

# Jaiku | Jaiku Privacy Policy

By using the Jaiku.com web site (the "Service"), a service of Jaiku Ltd. ("Jaiku"), you accept the following privacy statement (the “Privacy Statement”). In addition to the Service, Jaiku also provides you with a client application for your mobile phone (the "Software"), which may be downloaded by you from the Jaiku web site, or in the future pre-installed by the phone manufacturer or mobile operator, copied from a Jaiku user over Bluetooth or downloaded from some third-party partner web sites. This Privacy Statement applies also to the installation and use of the Software. 

You are also aware of our Terms of Use located on the Jaiku.com web site. Using the Service and the Software is governed also by the Terms of Use. In the event of inconsistency between this Privacy Statement and the Terms of Use, the Terms of Use shall prevail. 

Jaiku is committed to protecting your privacy. This Privacy Statement describes how Jaiku collects and receives personal information, how Jaiku uses the personal information and how Jaiku may share the personal information that it collects and receives. Personal information is information about you that is personally identifiable like your name, address, email address, or phone number. When you register with Jaiku, your personal information and other data will be stored and processed in Finland and this information will be subject to the laws of Finland. 

Children under 13 years of age are not permitted to use the Service. 

## How we collect and use your personal information

### General

  * Jaiku collects personal information when you sign up with Jaiku to use the Service and/or the Software and each time you use the Service and/or the Software.
  * When you sign up with Jaiku we ask for your name and email address. In the future you will be able to add certain optional information to your profile, such as your address, home town, birth date, gender, biographical information, instant messaging user names, and personal interests. By entering your personal information in the Service or by otherwise disclosing your personal information to us, you also accept and give your explicit consent that your personal information may be transferred, to the maximum extent permitted by applicable laws, across international borders to a location outside the country of your location.
  * If you would like to use our text messaging service or download the Software to your mobile phone, we will ask for your mobile phone number.
  * If you would like to obtain a paid account in the future, we will ask for your billing address, phone number, and credit card information.
  * Jaiku automatically receives and records information on its server logs from your browser, including your IP address, cookie, and the page you request.
  * Jaiku also automatically receives and records information on its server logs from the Software, including your mobile network operator, cell ID, city, country, cell name, whether you are currently using the phone or whether the phone is idle, phone's ring profile, Bluetooth buddy/laptop/desktop count, the duration and description of current/previous/next calendar event, and an indication of whether a call is currently in progress (3G only).
  * Jaiku uses information for the following general purposes: provision of products and services (including displaying and sending targeted advertisements on or through the Service, the Software or SMS), billing (in case of premium services), identification and authentication, contact, research and anonymous reporting.

### Use of cookies

Jaiku may use cookies on the Service and/or the Software. A cookie is a small file, which often includes an anonymous unique identifier, which is sent to your browser and stored on your computer's hard drive. 

  * If you do not wish to have cookies placed on your computer or wish to be notified when they are placed, you may set your browser to reject cookies or notify you of their use. If you reject all cookies, you will not be able to use those parts of the Service that require you to "sign in".
  * Jaiku uses its own cookies for a number of purposes, including but not limited to access your information when you "sign in"; keep track of preferences you specify while you are using the Service; and display the most appropriate advertising banners based on your activity on the Service.
  * Jaiku lets other companies that show advertisements on the Service sent and store cookies on your computer, subject to their own privacy policies. 

### How we share your personal information

  * When you post a message, your Jaiku ID or alias that you are posting under is visible to other users. If you post personal information online that is accessible to the public, you understand that you may receive unsolicited messages from other parties in return.
  * Generally, Jaiku does not share personal information about you with other people or nonaffiliated companies without your prior consent except to provide requested products or services or in the following circumstances: 
    * Jaiku may be required to disclose personally identifiable information under special circumstances, such as to comply with legal requirements or to exercise its legal rights;
    * It may be necessary to share information in order to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding suspected or actual illegal activities on or through the Service or the Software, including but not limited to violations of the Terms of Use or infringement of third party intellectual property rights, or as otherwise permitted or required by applicable laws;
    * Jaiku may share aggregated demographic information with its business partners. This is not linked to any personally identifiable information that can identify any individual person without your prior consent; and
    * In the event Jaiku enters into a joint venture or is acquired by or merged with another business entity, we may disclose your personal Information to our business partners or new owners.

## How you can edit or delete your account information

  * You can edit your Jaiku account information at any time; and
  * You can delete your Jaiku account at any time from your account page; however, please note that your identification, billing and contact information may remain in Jaiku's records for some period after the deletion.

## How we can modify this Privacy Statement

You understand that we are continuously developing the features and the functionality of the Service and the Software. Consequently, we also reserve the right to modify this Privacy Statement at any time in our sole discretion. You agree that such alteration shall be effective upon posting on the Jaiku.com web site and you will be bound to any alterations when you use the Service after such alteration is posted. It is therefore important that you review this Privacy Statement regularly on the Jaiku.com web site to ensure you are updated regarding any alterations. Your sole remedy should you not agree with the altered Privacy Statement shall be to close your account and to cease using the Service and the Software. 

## Any questions

If you have questions or suggestions, or would like to review your personal information stored by us, please contact us. Or, you can reach us by post at: 

Jaiku Ltd., Pieni Rooberinkatu 7, 00130 Helsinki, Finland 

Official File Description (rekisteriseloste) for the Jaiku web service.
